A Guide to the John D. Rockefeller 3rd papers, Associates, Datus C. Smith Jr. papers FA784
Rockefeller Archive Center
John D. Rockefeller 3rd papers, Associates, Datus C. Smith Jr. papers
1953, 1957-1974
Rockefeller Archive Center
Smith, Datus C., Jr.
Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison), 1906-1978
FA784
4.56 Cubic Feet 12 document boxes.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: correspondence, brochures and pamphlets, minutes, and newspaper articles
Arrangement
Alphabetical
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Biographical / Historical
Datus C. Smith Jr. was directly involved with a broad scope of organizations that John D. Rockefeller 3rd either founded or actively participated in such as the Asia Society and the Japan Society. He also assisted in the formulation and development of Mr. Rockefeller's activities in support the role of philanthropy in U.S. society (Peterson and Filer Commissions). Additionally, Smith also led the JDR 3rd Fund's Asian Cultural Program.
- Arts, Business and The Arts, Business Committee for the Arts, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Asia Society, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Asia Society, 1971-1974, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Asia Society, Djakarta Museum Project, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Committee for Economic Development, 1968-1968, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Diamond, Henry L., Calendar, Large, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Diamond, Henry L., Calendar, Desk, 1968 January-June (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Diamond, Henry L., Calendar, Desk, 1968 July-December (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Diamond, Henry L., Chronology File, 1968 January-August (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Diamond, Henry L., Chronology File, 1968 September-1969 March (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Federalist, Federalism Seventy-Six, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- General, 1965, 1967-1968, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- General, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- General Correspondence, 1968, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- General Correspondence, 1971 January-March (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Gifts, 1965, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- ISMUN, The International Student Movement for the United Nations, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- JDR 3rd Fund, Compliance, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- JDR 3rd Fund, Corporate, 1963-1964, 1967-1971, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- JDR 3rd Fund, Finance, 1964-1973 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- JDR 3rd Fund, General, 1963, 1967-1974 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- JDR 3rd Fund, General, 1963, 1967-1974 (Box 3, Folder 21A)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted from scholarly access-Confidential materials
- JDR 3rd Fund, Projects Adopted, 1967-1972 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- JDR 3rd Fund, Youth General, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Museums, 1961-1962, 1965, 1967-1970, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- National Endowment for the Humanities, 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Philanthropy, Asia, General Correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Philanthropy, Asia, Memoranda & Correspondence, 1962, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Philanthropy, Commission, 1968-1974 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Philanthropy, General, 1962-1963, 1966-1970 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Philanthropy, General, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Philanthropy, Legislation, 1953, 1963, 1969-1972 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Philanthropy, Legislation, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Philanthropy, Other Countries, 1962-1963, 1968-1973 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Population, Abortion, Law Reform, 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Population, Abortion, Law Reform, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Public Relations Conference, 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Public Service Awards, 1969-1970, 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, 1972, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, Booklets and Correspondence, 1957-1968, 1960-1961, 1963-1967 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, Booklets and Correspondence, 1959-1960, 1962-1963, 1965-1968 (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, Correspondence: Trip and Award Ceremonies, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, General Correspondence, 1963, 1965-1968 (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, Newspaper Clippings, 1957-1959, 1963, 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, Projected Budgets, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, The Wilkinson Fund, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 45)
- Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1970-1973 (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Contributions 1967, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 47)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Contributions 1968 (Box 7, Folder 48)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Contributions 1969 (Box 7, Folder 49)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Contributions 1970 (Box 7, Folder 50)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Contributions 1971, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 51)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Contributions 1972, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 52)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Chronology File, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 53)
- Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group (SEADAG), Asia Society, 1972-1974 (Box 8, Folder 54)
- Urban Home Ownership Corporation, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 55)
- Yankelovich, Daniel, Surveys, 1971-1974 (Box 8, Folder 56)
- China, 1969, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 57)
- Hong Kong, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 58)
- India, Foundations, 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 59)
- India, General, 1968-1973 (Box 8, Folder 60)
- India, General Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 61)
- India, International House, 1961, 1964, 1967-1968, 1970, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 62)
- India, National Centre for the Performing Arts, 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 63)
- Indonesia, International Secretariat for Volunteer Service (ISVS), 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 64)
- Iran, 1968-1969, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 65)
- Japan, General, 1966, 1968-1973 (Box 8, Folder 66)
- Japan, General Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 67)
- Japan, Japan Society, Program Review Committee, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 68)
- Korea, 1966-1968 (Box 9, Folder 69)
- Malaysia, 1967, 1969, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 70)
- Nepal, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 71)
- Pakistan, 1968-1970, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 72)
- Philippines, 1968-1970 (Box 9, Folder 73)
- Singapore, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 74)
- Thailand, 1968-1970 (Box 9, Folder 75)
- A, 1969-1973 (Box 9, Folder 76)
- American Assembly, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 77)
- Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1967-1968, 1970-1973 (Box 9, Folder 78)
- B, 1968-1973 (Box 9, Folder 79)
- C, 1969-1972 (Box 9, Folder 80)
- Choudhury, Golam Wahed, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 81)
- Chinese Culture Foundation of San Francisco, 1967-1970 (Box 9, Folder 82)
- The Edna McConnell Clark Foundation, 1971-1973 (Box 9, Folder 83)
- Council for Financial Aid to Education, Inc., 1970-1973 (Box 9, Folder 84)
- Cuninggim, Merrimon, 1968-1972 (Box 9, Folder 85)
- D, 1970-1973 (Box 10, Folder 86)
- E, 1968-1973 (Box 10, Folder 87)
- F, 1967-1968, 1970-1973 (Box 10, Folder 88)
- G, 1969, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 89)
- K, 1968-1973 (Box 10, Folder 90)
- L, 1968-1973 (Box 10, Folder 91)
- M, 1968-1973 (Box 10, Folder 92)
- N, 1968, 1971-1973 (Box 10, Folder 93)
- New Federalist Papers, 1971-1973 (Box 10, Folder 94)
- Nielsen, Waldemar A., 1968-1973 (Box 10, Folder 95)
- O, 1968-1969, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 96)
- P, 1968-1973 (Box 10, Folder 97)
- Peterson, Peter G., 1970 June-October (Box 11, Folder 98)
- Peterson, Peter G., 1970 November-1971 June (Box 11, Folder 99)
- R, 1968-1973 (Box 11, Folder 100)
- Rockefeller, John D., IV, 1968-1970, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 101)
- Rockefeller Center Luncheon Club, 1970-1971, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 102)
- S, 1970-1973 (Box 11, Folder 103)
- Sarabhai Family, 1968, 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 104)
- Schudson, Michael, 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 105)
- Shuman, Jim, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 106)
- Stern Fund, 1968-1972 (Box 11, Folder 107)
- The Student Vote, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 108)
- T, 1968-1973 (Box 12, Folder 109)
- Talbot, Phillips, 1968-1969, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 110)
- U, 1968, 1970, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 111)
- V, 1969-1973 (Box 12, Folder 112)
- W, 1969-1973 (Box 12, Folder 113)
- Wharton, Dolores, 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 114)
- X, Y, Z, 1968-1973 (Box 12, Folder 115)